准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
海绵宝宝的圣诞之路
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
裤头村
哒哒
Ta da
圣诞老人收
这礼物是送给圣诞老人的
This gift is for Santa Claus
圣诞老人也得有礼物  对吧小蜗
Even Santa deserves a gift, right Gary?
圣诞老人  圣诞老人
Santa Claus, Santa Claus
他就要来了
Santa's on his way
我要送他一份礼物
I'm giving him a present
让他带到雪橇上
That he'll take back on his sleigh
对啊  我都忘了
Oh, yeah, I forgot
缩小术
Shrink-o
圣诞老人收
七个月后
不好意思  沙发先生
Excuse me, Mr. Sofa
看啊  小蜗
Look at that, Gary
是我去年圣诞节留给圣诞老人的礼物
It's the present I left for Santa last Christmas
是不是很棒啊
Isn't that nice?
去年圣诞节留给圣诞老人的礼物
The present I left for Santa last Christmas
他没收到
He never got it
这坏事坏得不能再坏了
This is the worst disaster that's ever happened
我给圣诞老人的礼物迟到了212天
My present to Santa is 212 days late
迟到了  真是个悲剧
Late, it's a tragedy
我快乐逍遥的世界变得既黑暗又沉闷
My joyful carefree world is growing dark and dreary
我活不了了
I can't go on
不行  要继续活
No, I'll go on
可我真活不了了
But I can't go on
五星好演技
Five stars
派大星  我这不是在演戏
Patrick, I wasn't acting
圣诞老人没收到圣诞礼物
Santa never got his Christmas present
那为啥不亲自送给人家
So why not just deliver it to him?
为啥不亲自送给人家
Why not just deliver it to him?
这想法太扯了
That's a dumb idea
我加入
I'm in
太棒了
Great
可是要怎么过去
But how will we get there?
走路走不了那么远
We can't walk that far
咱俩可以互相推过去
We can push and shove each other
好办法
Great idea
咱一天都不能再迟下去了
We can't let it be one more day late
行了  你先推我
Okay, me first
轮我了
My turn
什么鬼
What the--
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
现在不是七月吗
It's July?
海之霸
今天是个当坏人的好日子
It's a good day to be bad
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
你鼻子上有干鼻涕
You got a booger
放心  朋友间就该互帮互助
Don't worry, that's what friends are for
擤出来
Blow
谢谢你
Thank you
这是我见过最丑的鼻涕了
It's the ugliest booger I've ever seen
你们两个疯子走路能别老是摔着吗
Can't you screwballs walk without falling?
抱歉  痞老板
Sorry Plankton
我们要把自己一路推到北极去
We're pushing and shoving ourselves
all the way to the North Pole
我必须要把礼物给圣诞老人
I have to give Santa his Christmas present
圣诞老人
Santa?
我恨死那家伙了
I hate that guy
自从我留了这个刺青以来
He's had me on a naughty list
他就一直把我记在淘气名单上
ever since I got this tattoo
生来淘气
等一下
Wait a minute
要是我能打入圣诞老人基地内部
If I can break into Santa's lair
黑进他的主机
hack his mainframe
把我状态从淘气改成善良
change my status from naughty to nice
我就能向他要蟹黄堡的秘密配方
I could ask for the Krabby Patty secret formula
然后他就非把它给我不可了
and he'd have to give it to me
我跟你们一起去
I'm coming with you
我来推一把吧
Pushed or shoved?
别这么搞
Shrimp that
我们要风风光光地过去  宝贝
We are going in style, babies
海之霸
我为了在僵尸末日期间
I built it to fly and run over bodies
飞天顺便碾压尸体特别打造的
during the zombie apocalypse
不过在雪上行驶也挺管用
but it'll work on snow too
我们要从太平洋走到北冰洋
We'll take the Pacific to the Arctic
然后越过冰雪到达北极
then over ice and snow to the North Pole
轻轻松松就能到圣诞老人那儿
Easy-peasy, Santa-squeezy
海顶两万里
安全带
Seat belts
确实  安全第一
Of course, safety first
一切就绪  痞老板船长
All secured, Captain Plankton
一切就绪
All secured
我已经后悔要跑这一趟了
I'm already regretting this trip
点火
蟹堡王
我们成功了
We did it
快看那些小鱼崽子
Look at those tiny little fish
嗨
Hi
回位子上坐好
Get back to your seats
安全带指示灯没亮
The seat belt sign is off
天外来客来了
The visitors, they're here
他见到我们貌似很高兴
He seemed happy to see us
会飞的躺椅
A flying lawn chair
拿来吧你
Give me that
盒子里面的是个啥东西
What's in this box anyway?
是个惊喜
It's a surprise
希望是用来炸那啤酒肚小丑的臭气弹
I hope it's a stink bomb
for that pot-bellied jingle joker
圣诞老人才没有啤酒肚
Santa is not pot-bellied
他只是患了季节性腹胀罢了
He just suffers from seasonal bloating
行行行
Right
我要睡觉去了
I'm going to sleep
可这玩意要谁来开
But who will fly this thing?
我设成自动驾驶模式了
I put it on automatic pilot
你跟那个粉红傻蛋可以打地铺
You and that pink moron can sleep on the floor
你们两个白痴在搞什么鬼
What are you imbeciles doing?
我们找到北极了
We found the North Pole
北极比你说的要近多了
It was way closer than you said
北极
North Pole?
不可能啊
Impossible
我睡多久了
How long was I asleep?
地面越来越近感觉好奇怪
Funny how the ground keeps getting closer
圣诞世界主题乐园
欢迎来到圣诞世界主题乐园
Welcome to Christmas Land Theme Park
在这天天都是圣诞节
Where every day is Christmas
滚出我的位子
Get out of my seat
安全带指示灯亮了
The seat belt sign is on
机组人员  准备降落
Cabin crew, prepare for landing
你真的会降落吗
Do you actually know how to land?
我会坠落
I know how to crash land
我的安全带
My seat belt
是北极
The North Pole
北极
我们到了
We made it
看看你们两个脑残搞了什么鬼
Look what you two broken brain buffoons did
你们彻底把导航弄坏了
You completely destroyed the navigation system
不客气
You're welcome
别生气嘛  痞老板
Don't be mad, Plankton
咱都到了
We're here
看看这好地方
Look at all this
糖果
圣诞老人的精灵
Santa's elves
圣诞老人的驯鹿
Santa's reindeer
真是太神了
This is amazing
有点不对劲
Something's wrong here
这里居然不冷
It isn't even cold
而且看看这雾霾
And look at this smog
既有雪又有雾霾
It's snow and smog?
那叫雪霾
It's "snog"
圣诞老人的工厂
Santa's workshop
做玩具  勤工作
Making toys, work, work, work
圣诞老人的精灵们好
Hello, Santa's elves
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas
做  勤
Make, work--
圣诞老人已经尽力实现自动化生产了
Looks like Santa's gone all in for automation
见圣诞老人
圣诞主题公厕
大家快看
Hey guys, look
上面写着  见圣诞老人
It says, "meet Santa Claus"
见圣诞老人
都快来
Come on, guys
去见圣诞老人
Let's meet Santa
我们总算到了  小礼物
We're finally here, little present
见真正的
圣诞老人
我不得不说  这地方太假了
Guys, I hate to say this, but this place is a sham
总有种被骗的感觉
I don't know why, but we're being tricked
痞老板  圣诞节的精髓在于信仰
Oh, Plankton, Christmas is about believing
确实  圣诞节的精髓于血样
Yeah, Christmas is about bleeding, man
要不是亲眼见到连我都不信
I wouldn't believe it if I didn't see it with my own eye
是那个大胡子奇葩本人
The bearded weirdo in the flesh
你们圣诞节想要什么礼物
What would you like for Christmas?
静一静  孩子们
Pipe down, children
什么
What the--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants?
嗨  圣诞老人
Hi, Santa
你知不知道我是你的头号粉丝
Did you know that I'm your biggest fan?
你真好心  圣诞老人
That's very sweet of you Santa
不过其实海盗派斯才是我的头号粉丝
but actually Patchy the Pirate is my biggest fan
你们好啊  海绵宝宝派大星
Ahoy, SpongeBob and Patrick
是我海盗派斯
It's me, Patchy the Pirate
海盗派斯
Patchy the Pirate?
你居然是圣诞老人
You're Santa?
不对  我只是在圣诞乐园扮圣诞老人
No, I just play Santa here in Christmas Land Theme Park
这是我的副业
It's me side-hustle
我就知道这不是北极
I knew this wasn't the North Pole
北极
North Pole?
不对  这可是恩斯诺
No, man, this be Encino
你们离北极还有四千英里远
You're almost 4,000 miles from the North Pole
我要把你们俩都灭了
I'm gonna destroy you two
四千英里
4,000 miles?
要是GPS没坏就好了
If only our GPS wasn't busted
我可以帮你们导航
I can help with global positioning
在GPS发明以前
Way before GPS
海盗都用这种叫地图的东西
pirates used these things called maps
你们也会需要用到指南针
And you'll need a compass too
圣诞快乐
Happy holidays
死鹦鹉想挨揍是吧
Polly want a smacker?
那谢谢了  派斯
Well, thanks, Patchy
我们该上路去了
Guess we'll be on our way
再见
Goodbye
祝你们好运
Good luck
要是见到圣诞老人  就说我要换鹦鹉
If you see Santy Claus, tell him I want a new parrot
我要换个新海盗
And I want a new pirate
恩斯诺
等等  我们这是在哪
Wait, where are we?
北极
圣诞老人工厂  就在前方
S-S-Santa's workshop, dead ahead
刚好赶到
J-j-just in time
我快冻死了
I'm f-f-freezing
就要到了吗
Are we there yet?
北极
你这痞老板冰棍好吃不
How you doing with that Plankton pop?
我等不及要吃有嚼劲的夹心了
I can't wait to get to the chewy middle
派大星  痞老板哪去了
Hey Patrick, where's Plankton?
不知道
I don't know
吃点口香糖吧你  小臭嘴
Eat a breath mint, trench mouth
那好吧  我要敲门了
All right, here it goes
你们样子好好看哦
You guys look great
我好喜欢你们的宇航头盔
I like your spaceman helmets
可是还要再过三个月才过万圣节的呢
But it's not Halloween for another three months
我们不是来过万圣节的
We're not here for Halloween
是来找圣诞老人的
we're here for Santa
我有自己的日程安排
I've got my own agenda
所以说到这咱就分道扬镳吧
so this is where we part company
真对不起  圣诞老人不在的呢
Sorry, Santa's not home
他跟太太在阿鲁巴
He's in Aruba with the Missus
不过
But
还是给你们这个吧
here you go anyway
可是
But--
万圣节快乐哦
Happy Halloween
是痞老板
That's Plankton
他进去了
He's inside
可真是
Jeez
我一定要把圣诞老人的礼物放他树下
I have to get Santa's present under his tree
咱必须得进去
We've got to get inside
包在我身上
I'm on it
有了
I know
用圣诞老人的风格进去
We'll go in Santa style
就顺着烟囱走
Down the chimney
行  就用你的办法了
Fine, we'll go with your idea
圣诞老人的主机到底在哪
Now where in Kris Kringle is Santa's mainframe?
没有主机
No mainframe
圣诞老人工厂
只有垃圾
just lame brains
你这是想去哪
Where do you think you're going?
是说我吗
Who, me?
我只是个小精灵
I'm just a little elf
你味道一点都不像精灵
You don't smell like no elf
是吗
Oh, yeah?
关你屁事  你个驼鹿
What's it to you, you moose?
戴什  当瑟
Dasher, Dancer
普兰瑟
Prancer
维克森  科密
Vixen, Comet
丘比特  唐纳
Cupid, Donner
布利岑
Blitzen
看样子圣诞专车都到齐了是吧
Well, looks like we got a whole Christmas special here
准备好来玩驯鹿游戏了吗
Ready for some reindeer games?
天下太平
Peace on earth?
你们蹄子上的玩意最好是泥巴
That better be mud on your hooves
就是这了
That's it
圣诞老人的圣诞树
Santa's Christmas tree
他们在那
There they are
是那些来要糖的
It's the trick-or-treaters
玩具贼
Toy thieves
圣诞骗子
Christmas crooks
抓住他们
Get 'em
海绵宝宝  要怎么办
SpongeBob, what do we do?
爬树
Climb
他们要上树了
They're going up the tree
别让他们跑了
Don't let 'em get away
圣诞老人工厂
警报响了  都去看看
We better check that alarm
被我弄累了是吧
I wore you down, didn't I?
你们这堆呆头傻鹿
You meat head cari-boobs
玩具贼
Toy thieves
精灵们
Elves
这到底是怎么回事
What the Father Christmas is going on here?
我们都已经控制住了
We got this under control
快回你们的鹿厩去
Go back to your stables
太过分了  精灵小弟
Not cool elf bros
一点都不好笑
Not funny
不好了  派大星
Oh, no, Patrick
我似乎把充满不满情绪的种子
It looks like I have sowed the seeds of discontent
播撒在圣诞老人的屋子里了
in the house of Santa
派大星
Patrick?
拐杖糖
Candy cane
圣诞老人的主机
Santa's mainframe
我找到了
I found it
善良名单添加
保存
痞老板
得亏有那两个白痴转移注意力
Thanks to those two idiots causing a distraction
我成功了
I did it
我名字已经写进善良名单上了
My name is the nice list
只要再连当几个月大善人就行了
Now I just gotta be good for the next few months
这有什么难的
How hard could that be?
这都怎么一回事
What the ho, ho, ho is going on here?
我在加勒比海跟太太正舒服着
I was kicking back with the Missus in the Caribbean
突然我的静音警报就响了
when my silent alarm went off
嗨  圣诞老人
Hi, Santa
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
我早该知道的
I should've known
你真是个麻烦精
You're a menace
我只想把你去年圣诞节
All I wanted to do was leave you this present
没收到的礼物给你
that you didn't get last Christmas
迟到了213天
213 days late
抱歉
Sorry
礼物永远都不嫌迟
A present is never too late
你真是好心
How sweet
精灵跟驯鹿都没送过我礼物
Not even the elves or reindeer get me presents
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
应该现在就打开吗
Should I open it now?
这份礼物独一无二
It's one of a kind
胶水
蟹黄堡的秘密配方
The Krabby Patty secret formula?
他要把它送给圣诞老人
He's giving it to Santa Claus
我还改什么名单  秘方就在眼前
Forget the list, the formula's right here
马上就能到我手上了
I could have it now
痞老板
Plankton?
你又在干淘气事了
You're being naughty
圣诞老人  我生来淘气
Santa, I was born to be naughty
生来淘气
好
Yeah
好吧
还是还给你吧
you can have this back
是我不好
My bad
我是说好
I mean, good--
是我好
my good
我很善良  一点都不淘气
I'm being nice, not naughty
你念出来
Well, read it out loud
没什么的
That's okay
快点  念出来
Go on, read it
念出来
Read it
亲爱的圣诞老人
"Dear Santa
世界上没有一份礼物能够大到
"there isn't a present big enough
能够足以表达你把多少欢乐带给了
"to express how much joy you've brought
全世界的小朋友和海底生物
"to all the children and sea creatures of the world
因此这其实只是份简单的感谢信
"So this is just a simple thank you note
谢谢你
"Thank you
爱你的  你的朋友海绵宝宝
Signed, with love, your pal SpongeBob"
上面有错别字
You got a typo here
好感动
How touching
真是太美好了
This is beautiful
谢谢你  海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
没痞老板帮忙我也没法顺利抵达的
I wouldn't have made it here
without the help of Plankton
他其实也没那么淘气的
He's really not that naughty
当然也少不了好朋友派大星的帮忙
And of course, my best friend Patrick
派大星
Patrick?
祝我圣诞快乐
Happy holidays to me
第二年圣诞节
蟹堡王
给你
Here you go
祝大家圣诞快乐
Happy holidays, everybody
谢尔顿
Sheldon
煤块
Lump of coal
圣诞快乐  痞老板
Merry Christmas, Plankton
肯定又是煤块
Another lump of coal no doubt
这是什么
What's this?
祝痞老板圣诞快乐
你总有一天能灭掉我们
我会的  海绵宝宝
Yes, I will, SpongeBob
我会的
Yes, I will
毁灭吧
Destroy